hello friends welcome back to this
channel again
you know that in this channel we analyze
different
sectors in uh indian stock market
we analyze um different uh mutual funds
in various sectors like elsa's large cup
mid cap
small cap etc so in today's video we're
going to talk about
insulin sector so we have mainly
five companies in insurance sector and
we are going to
run a quantitative analysis on all these
companies like iclc lumbar general
insurance
hdfc life general insurance card portion
of india
icici pro life insurance and spi life
now based on several fundamental
parameters like
sales growth profit growth
return on equity their earning
visibility
values and metrics etc so based on all
these different fundamental parameters
we are going to give clients so the
company which is scoring
highest point will be ranked first and
then followed by the other companies
so this is how we are going to run this
analysis and also we
did similar analysis in other sectors
like
we we uploaded a video on paint sector
on i.t sector chemical specialty
chemical
sector and also fmcg sector
if you want to take a look at those
videos so please
um go to the video section in this
channel and you can
have a look now let's get started in
this video about our insurance sector
analysis
now these are the companies as i already
said in the previous
uh slide you can see as per the
market capitalization i have arranged
them in this order
hdfc live has market capitalization of
one point four three lakh
rupees sbi life has market cap of about
ninety eight thousand crore rupees i say
i say pro life about
eighty three thousand crore rupees ici
lumbered about sixty
nine point seven uh thousand crore
uh rupees and general insurance about
thirty five thousand crore
rupees market capitalization now from
these uh companies we are going to run
this quantitative analysis now
in the next slide let me show you how we
do it
now uh first let's let's start with the
uh three years sales growth now
this sales growth number are taken from
different websites okay mainly we follow
either
ticker tape or uh screener dot in and
now
if you go to different companies and if
i
take a look at three years else grow
these are the numbers as you can see in
the middle
column as it is like three ourselves
growth thirty point four percentage svi
like thirty four percentage i say i say
true life
twenty eight point nine percentage i say
say lumbar 20.8 percentage and
general insurance 24.7 percentage so you
can see that
the the the company which has the
highest sales growth is svi live 34
percentage
and then it will be hdfc live there then
it will be icsa pro live then it will be
general insurance and icici lumber
so we have given points according to
their sales growth numbers since sva
life
is having the highest sales growth so we
give five points
because we have five companies right
then it will be hdfc live
followed by icsa pro-life then general
insurance
and the last will be icici lumber so in
this way
we are going to analyze all different
parameters
right and at the end what we are going
to do is we are going to collect all
these points
for each and every company we will add
them up
and show you the final result and then
you can
realize fundamentally which company is
strong or stronger and then you can take
a decision
however whatever companies we are
talking about in this video
are not for any direct recommendation
you should always discuss with your
advisor before taking any position in
these companies
let me uh come back to the analysis
again
five year sales growth five year sales
point of view you can see
again svi life is having
five year sense growth of 33.5
percentage which is the highest
in this list therefore it will get five
points and the lowest is
again i say lumbar only 15.1 percentage
therefore we will give it only one point
right and you can see the points and the
sales growth number for other companies
as well
in the slide next profit growth
now first let's talk about three years
profit growth three years profit growth
perspective you can see icici lombard
it is uh presenting three years profit
growth
36 percentage therefore we are giving it
five point and the lowest in this case
is icsi proof
like minus 23.4 percentage
therefore we are giving it one point for
general insurance we could not find the
data therefore we are not considering it
for
particularly this analysis five years
profit growth five years profit growth
perspective
also you can see icici lombard is
presenting the highest
five years profit growth twenty three
point eight percentage therefore it will
get
highest five points and ics a true life
with the lowest five years profit code
minus 15.1 percentage therefore it will
get the
lowest point one point now if i
talk about return on capital employed
okay so again you can see that from the
roce perspective you can see icici
lumber
is reporting the highest roc value
26.8 percentage therefore we give it
five points
and the lowest in this list is for
general insurance
which is reporting only minus point
minus four point one seven therefore
only
one point what about five years uh
roc five years return on capital
employed
here again icsa lumbar you can see
25.9 percentage five years roc e
therefore we give it five points and the
lowest
is for general insurance which will get
only one point because it is reporting
only four point nine eight percentage of
five years roc
now what about just return on equity if
you take a look at
return on equity only again you can see
that
i see a lumbar 21.6 percentage
therefore it will get five points
and general insurance again is scoring
lowest because it is reporting negative
3.37 percentage
so at least from up to this uh if you
have some idea about how
this company particularly is a lumber is
scoring
uh high in all the front
but let's not stop here let me continue
um and i would like to remind you again
if you
think that this analysis is interesting
please like the video
please uh share with your friends and
um and and subscribe to our channel
so that you can get more and more
information on
uh different sectors right so five years
return on acuity
we have already discussed i think um
okay so in the case of five years roe
the highest scorer is uh hdfc live
because it is supporting 21.4 percentage
ro
e five years roe therefore it will get
five points
and the lowest or the the lowest quality
is again
general insurance with only four point
six two percentage five years away
therefore it will get one point
now operating profit margin operating
profit margin
is the highest for icici lombard
uh 12 percentage therefore it will get
four points and the lowest
is for ic is a potential life only
minus 0.41 percentage therefore it will
get the lowest
one point and you can see the operating
profit margin for other companies as
well as the
points that we have given to these
companies what about
five years operating profit margin five
years operating profit margin again
icici lombard with 11.1 percentage
therefore it will get five points and
the lowest in this case is
general insurance with operating five
years operating profit margin of
minus zero point four five percentage
therefore it will get only
one point now dead two equity so how
much
is dead compared to equity um you can
see that svi life
and general insurance they are basically
their free companies therefore they will
get the highest point five points to
each companies
okay and that from rest of the companies
you can see
icsa prove has the highest date 0.1
therefore it will get only one point and
you can see the points for other
companies as well
now um fi plus dii holdings out of the
total free float market capitalization
so this is basically
if you take any company to total
holdings and then if you subtract the
promoters holding
okay so you get free float market
capitalization of that particular
company
now out of this free float market
capitalization
how much is the holding total holdings
for uh for administration investor plus
domestic institutional investor for fi
plus dii
okay so you can see the the numbers okay
these are the numbers that we have
calculated
you don't really get this total number
um
in other websites so we have to
calculate this and what we have found is
that ic is a lumbar
um and the total holdings could be as
high as 85.28 percentage therefore it
will get
five points and the lowest in this list
is hdfc live
77.58 percentage okay therefore
only one point but i would like to make
one point here that almost all the
companies for all the companies the
total institutional holdings is really
good
and that shows that how institutional
investors are
really on this insurance sector they are
really looking
for growth and um growth in this sector
right
this is the last parameter that we are
going to discuss here
price to earnings rate ratio or
pe ratio so generally
um when somebody wants to discuss or
somebody wants to
talk about let's say taking position
many people think that we have to
really purchase the companies with a
very low pe
but that's not always correct right you
have to run a complete
quantitative analysis okay on you have
to analyze the companies in a particular
sector
from all the corners not only based on
only one parameter like pe
or sales or revenue growth or profit
growth
so like this you have to run from all
the corner you
try to analyze the companies in a
particular sector and then only you take
position right
so from pe ratio perspective you can see
the lowest pe
is general insurance so you may think
that maybe this is very attractive
company
right but you will see in the next slide
when we publish the
final result that maybe if you are
thinking that i will go and buy
general insurance because it has the
lowest pe maybe you will be wrong
um okay it's possible so
since uh general insurance has the
lowest p
so we give it five points and you can
see the pe for other companies as well
and you can see i see i say prove life
it has pe of
188.15 it is insane
and because of this so much high pe or
the highest pe
it will get only one point so till now
we have
um completed all the parameters that we
wanted to
include this um analysis okay this is
about um i think 13 to 14 parameters and
now you noted all these plans
uh for a particular company and then we
added them
and the next slide i'm going to show you
the
final result but before that i'd like to
give a small
stop and i would like you to write the
final score what do you think that is
the
scorer here okay so stop
all right i think you got it um
the name so now let me show you the uh
winner here here icsa lombard it is
scoring 55 which is highest among all
these
other companies okay therefore it will
um
rank number one next is sbi life
51 point rank 2 hdfc live
45 rank 3 i say i say pro life
28 rank 4 general insurance 28
rank 4. okay so this is very crucial now
um so so many people had
um some bias towards some companies in
the list but
maybe i also have some bias but when i
run this analysis it is very clear that
if i take a look from all the points all
the corners
which company is uh standing out
right so this is how we analyze all the
other sectors
and uh and if you if you want us to
analyze some other sectors
okay so please let us know in the
comment box now which sector you'd like
us to do the further analysis and we'll
do it and will present in front of you
and if you like this
work please um like the video you share
with your friends
and subscribe to this channel and please
you
hit the bell icon so that you get all
the notification
whenever we upload a video so
finally i thank all of you for your
attention
and have your time bye